ELIZABETH STONE

(406) 224-2936 • lizzystone13@gmail.com • Boston, MA linkedin.com/in/its-liz • github.com/liztheshiz • liztheshiz.github.io/portfolio-website

WEB DEVELOPER

Thoughtful developer skilled in workplace relationships and quick grasp of new concepts and skills. Experienced in a wide array of web development technologies like JavaScript, React, cloud deploy architecture, and API development. Strong understanding of big-picture quality and workflow.

Skilled in:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- React
- AWS
- Git + GitHub

- Node + npm
- MongoDB
- Browser compatibility
- Responsive design
- Bootstrap
- API development
- Test-driven development
- PostgreSQL + NoSQL

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry | Cloud Computing for Web Developers (Remote)

Oct 2022-Feb 2023

- Developed and deployed fully integrated web app on AWS, optimized by AWS standards in computing efficiency, security, and reliability
- Independently completed AWS training course and sitting AWS CCP certification exam in Feb.

CareerFoundry | Full-Stack Web Development Certification (Remote)

Apr 2022-Sept 2022

- Developed six web apps from scratch with feedback from industry professionals, including:
 - o Multiple sites written entirely in vanilla HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
 - o Single-page web app built with React and Bootstrap
 - o MongoDB database and Express API for use with two frontend projects
 - o Progressive web app that uses Google OAuth2 for authentication
 - o Native real-time mobile chat app written in React Native
- Learned and utilized common development practices like Agile, TDD, and Kanban boards

Cornell University | BA in Italian Studies

Aug 2014-Dec 2018

- Accolades: 3.91 GPA, Dean's List 4/4 years
- Non-major studies: Computer Science, Sound Design, Physics of Musical Sound, Philosophy

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Fleet Service Agent | American Airlines | Boston, MA

Nov 2021-present

- Coordinate with small, specialized team to complete ground services for on-time departures
- Push back several \$130 million aircraft every day, after becoming one of handful of employees to complete pushback training in their first 100 days of employment
- Carry hundreds of bags of up to 75lbs each day, keeping pace with stronger male colleagues

Archival Assistant | Jean Locey, Professional Photographer & Cornell Professor Jan 2019-Dec 2021

- Planned and executed digitization of Prof. Locey's lifelong collection of over 250 images of professional film photography work, to be archived, printed, and/or uploaded to her website
- Edited each of the 250 digital images, using Photoshop to manually adjust contrast and color balance to accurately match original finished works, to Prof. Locey's specifications

ADDITIONAL DEV EXPERIENCE

ArtCenter Game Jam | ArtCenter College of Design | San Francisco, CA (Remote) Jan 2021-Mar 2021

- Collaborated with small team to design, develop, and deploy a game in 72 hours
- Produced original music carefully written to meet the practical needs and tone of the game